Welcome to the next token. Today is
Friday, July 17th. I'm Dylan Mulroy and
this is a podcast about three developers
who don't have the time or energy to be
hosting a podcast.
>> Hey, I'm Reese Sullivan. I'm working on
my startup, Executa.
>> Uh hi, I'm Sunil Pai. I work at
Cloudflare. Uh so does Dylan and they
sponsor the show for us.
>> So, on today's show, uh we need to start
off by uh settling a bet. And we're
going to uh talk about the news and what
is top of mind for uh the three of us
over the past week or two since we last
recorded. And then today is the first of
probably many, but at least three
episodes focusing on each of our
workflows with AI and genetic
engineering and how we're doing this
day-to-day at our companies and day jobs
um and thinking about that. So, to get
started here, we need to uh settle a bet
we made at AI Engineer where we were
last recorded. Uh Sunil, you want to
explain to our audience?
>> this is Okay, so this is embarrassing
because
I consider myself a man of the world and
I don't like making bets that uh
that I lose.
Uh on while we were So, we were
recording right in the center of AIE
Expo and Fable was still like the
government was like it's still so uh
dangerous and we're not going to let it
out without
uh uh controls and which is why I think
even OpenAI were like, "Yeah, we can't
really roll out 5.6 to anyone."
And Dylan, you said that by the time the
next episode rolls around, we will have
access to Fable as well as 5.6.
And I very confidently I was like,
"Well, I'm letting you know."
>> Shush.
Uh I said, "Well, there's no chance
because the US government can't uh find
their hands uh
uh out of their arse or whatever the
phrase is."
Uh and I bet $10 against that. Uh Reese,
you decided to join me because I clearly
seem like the most uh
the smarter one of the lot and you said
$10.
>> [laughter]
>> I said it was going to be weeks or
months.
>> Months? You said like months.
>> take. I I either said weeks or months,
but I was like it's not going to It's
going to be a while.
>> And from the communications we've had
from OpenAI on the 5.6 rollout, it's
definitely It sounds like it's going to
be like weeks. Uh and so
>> Oh, sounds like I'm about to lose. 10
bucks? 20 bucks? My timeline's late.
Bucks.
>> July late July. Fable's coming back.
>> Like I Like it wasn't even about the
money. I just enjoy being right.
So, we did We recorded the whole episode
for like an hour and a half 2 hours. We
got off and within 10 minutes, Twitter
was a blaze that Fable is back and 5.6
is rolling out.
>> Right, right. Is it
So bad. Yeah, it was like literally we
had like gotten up from the the podcast
uh station which was like smack-dab
center of the Expo hall, like OpenAI's
booth with like hundreds of people
around it right beside us. Pull up our
phones and sure enough
uh
Fable was released and then a few days
later 5.6 was also released.
>> You have to understand like my my my
life is built around people like owing
me favors, okay? So, yeah.
>> Well, uh I will uh anxiously be awaiting
uh the Venmo transactions from both of
you, so I am up 20 bucks.
>> I'm good for it just so we're clear.
Like I'm in the UK, so this is like uh
like uh paper This money doesn't even
make sense to me, but I'm good for it,
okay? Uh we're trying to We don't do
Venmo here, like uh but I'm just saying
I'm good for it.
>> Yeah, sorry.
It may The check's in the mail. Check's
in the mail.
>> Perfect. Perfect. I'll I'll Venmo
request Reese. Reese, you want to kick
us off uh this week with what's top of
mind for you over the since we last
recorded?
>> Yeah, I
I wanted to talk on [music]
OpenAI versus Anthropic's comms game
because
>> like they both had really bad
communication
6 months ago ish
and OpenAI kind of they locked in a bit
in terms of like
I don't like the changes are so small in
terms of they just kind of improved
their communication game a little bit by
being like hey this is what we're
planning on doing. This is what we're
doing actively and this is like what
we're seeing.
And so I got some like
tweets here where
one was the first one of like how
Anthropic handled the extension of rate
limits or the extension of favorable
access to on the
>> Oh right right right.
>> So I like
I don't know I don't just like
they can do whatever they want with the
model. It more just like confuses me
from a perspective of like
if you're going to have to make this
decision anyways to extend it like
this it seems like something that you
could communicate up front in terms of
like
like if I think about how OpenAI would
have communicated this it probably would
have been something along lines of like
hey here's the new model it's like
limited capacity but we want to see like
how people are using it what you can do
with it and depending on the capacity or
usage we have like we'll see see if we
can extend it in the future that kind of
thing.
>> Yeah just like
transparent almost like
>> Yeah.
>> owning the reality of the situation
they're in.
>> Yeah and the other thing is like
I've I've seen rumors on Twitter of like
them trying to do like a distilled Opus
5 or something like that. So like maybe
that's another thing where like they
have this other model that's coming out
soon.
>> Do you think that OpenAI releasing
5/6 Soul, Terra, and Luna, kind of
forced
Anthropic's hand here to extend
the limits. And
in the same vein, I think a a second
question I have is like
do you think this is coming from them
having scarcity around compute and them
genuinely struggling to be able to serve
the inference for these models?
Yeah, I guess that would be my my my two
questions around around this topic
because I I still to this day have not
used Fable at all.
Uh I don't have an Anthropic
subscription and because
uh Fable does not support zero data
retention, we don't have access to it in
Cloudflare. And many enterprises don't
because zero data retention is a very
important characteristic of really any
uh third-party service that enterprises
use.
>> Yeah, I mean I I I assume that they
limited just I wish that I knew more
about how the inference of it works
because like I would have assumed that
like the night before Fable was was
taken away with a bunch of people
hammering their max plans thinking that
it would like trying to get all of their
usage used up cuz they're like, well,
this is going away, so I'm just going to
like burn my tokens.
>> Yeah.
>> I like would have expected that I would
have expected to see more people
reporting errors on Twitter of like, oh,
it's at capacity or like like getting
those use like getting uh capacity
issues. And there didn't seem to be any
of those.
>> I'm curious if like enterprises that are
building products
over API, who are doing like way heavier
load,
maybe have seen
that in higher
um
in higher numbers. Actually, that's a
great question for everyone listening.
If you work at a company that is
building products around uh Anthropic
models, uh especially Fable, during this
time period where they were kind of
extending the limits for Fable post GPT
56 rollout. Did you see
availability issues, error rates
increase on your products and in your
telemetry?
>> Yeah, I'd be interested to know how
people building AI products are also
like
like I I assume that
you wouldn't just immediately swap to
running everything through Fable. In
that like it's a good model, but the
price jump the like price jump for
output seems like if you if you
didn't have a subsize it seemed weird to
me. Let's see. Then the other ones Oh,
another one was like they did a research
on July 15th
Claude did.
And that was also an interesting one to
me where it was like
like it it was just like a statement of
fact. We've done a reset. It wasn't like
a oh, we like love you guys using the
product. Like here's a like there there
was no fluff for it, which is maybe
appreciated. But it seems like if they
added fluff, it would again be like a
free kind of win just in terms of
sentiment. Whereas like
otherwise it just like it
you have all these like little
opportunities to like win like consumer
favor, I would say.
>> Yeah, yeah, for sure.
>> And I feel like they don't take
advantage of them. And but like the
other thing is they've
got like a pretty good product, you
know, like and maybe that's that's just
like in a position where they don't like
have to
care about that.
>> I I feel like that is shrinking away and
like I mean
both of these companies are
I think dealing with similar
adoption stories that like both
Cloudflare and Vercel for that matter
dealt with and I think both companies
are very good at and is that
and a lot of successful dev tool
companies over the past 10-15 years is
like target
like the developers for their hobby
projects outside of work, consulting,
contracting. And if you win the hearts
and minds of them for that type of work,
they're going to be your biggest
advocates
in the in you know, the enterprising
companies where like the real money is.
And right now, at least me personally,
like I have like
probably a borderline negative opinion
of Anthropic despite them having been
the company and their models that had,
you know, sold me on agentic engineering
being the future with Opus 45 and 46. Um
just the
I don't
like their stance or the way that to
your point, Reese, that they communicate
that like it just feels like they know
better than us and they
don't
care about all the feedback, it seems
like, that the developer community is
blatantly like
shouting about on Twitter. And Twitter's
a bubble, but like
regardless, right now, like
developers are and like coding use cases
are the places where these companies are
getting
the majority of their revenue revenue
from, at least in my understanding and
the the reporting that I've seen.
And
like I am far more likely
to go into Cloudflare and advocate for
OpenAI models right now, uh because
they're just more transparent in the way
they work. They seem like they're
actually working towards better token
economics and, you know,
usage. But I think both of these
companies are in a really tough place um
too, which we'll talk about here in a
little bit, uh which is what I want to
get into talking about.
>> Go ahead and say it, Neil.
>> Yeah, so about like 4 years ago, uh 5,
maybe, uh Cloudflare the big problem
that Cloudflare was facing was people
didn't know who they were.
Uh like they were like, "Oh, you have
some I thought you were a CDN company."
And the word CDN barely shows up in
marketing. And the thing that Cloudflare
did was well, we have all of these
people, let them tweet about what
they're working about online. Like we
don't we don't even want to like curate
the message. And what's happened now is
Cloudflare doesn't shut the up on
Twitter. Like they're just
>> [laughter]
>> non-stop all over it. And every like not
even like announcement weeks.
Announcement weeks we drown out everyone
for a week, right?
>> Yeah.
>> So you can see the same thing happening
in OpenAI. I don't know if it's
connected to the TVPN
acquisition, but there seems to be a
direct line there. All the DX boys, the
builders in residence, and the Codex
people are just talking about their
stuff all I mean, they just hi- hired
Polly Narvaez, one of the most
beloved community leaders, right?
>> Yep.
>> Uh that doesn't seem like a mistake to
me. I know for a fact Anthropic is very
uh I don't say hush-hush, but their
employees aren't really encouraged to
talk I mean, like company secrets,
whatever it is. They So, there is a
difference between Timothy saying, "Hey,
I pushed the reset button." versus the
official Claude
uh uh uh
Twitter account just saying, "Oh, like
limits are reset." And I think
to be clear, they're both
trillion-dollar companies, and I don't
want to simp for any of them. But
obviously, they're doing a a charm
offensive on the OpenAI side, right?
Uh I that maybe that's what maybe that's
what we're seeing. Yeah.
>> Yeah, it just like it's it's weird the
the thing that's weird to me like you
you had a
you like last point of like you had a
bit of just like companies it's like
there's not really a huge reason to be
attached to either. I don't think it
would like impact them that much to just
like slightly tweak their communication
style.
>> Uh
>> I have a proposal. I have a proposal.
Also, by the way, like this is related
to the last ad that Anthropic put down
where they had houses burning and
gravestones.
>> it was
>> [snorts]
>> so weird.
>> Such a bad idea. Okay, so here's my
proposal, okay? Let them have the same
messaging
uh like Dario's words even though
they're kind of weird. Pay George
Clooney and Sarah Ferguson $500 a year
to just say those words. Just look
extremely attractive on screen and say
that. I suspect it might help even a
little bit and they could use all the
help they could use have right now. Just
don't make the houses burning videos.
That's what I'm saying. You know?
>> It is so crazy and we should actually
maybe at one point soon do an episode or
have a segment about this but like
I recently was back home and I grew up
in
York Pennsylvania and I was around a
bunch of people that are not in the tech
community that are just you know typical
I know Pennsylvania's not really the the
Rust Belt or the Midwest but it shares a
lot of character list characteristics
like it and like even my friends and
family that I that I know are highly
educated and stuff man they have such
negative disposition
about AI and they have very incorrect
assumptions about how it works the
energy around it all these things and
like these kind of ads especially this
one and the way Dario in particular
talks about the future and these models
is
I think really really hurting the
potential not only these companies but
the the technology too and like honestly
like improving our energy
infrastructure.
>> Do you ever notice how whenever like the
AGI ASI people talk to you and they're
like here's all of the very detailed
ways it can go wrong and then you're
like what are the ways that
>> Yeah it always leads with the ways to go
wrong.
>> It always leads with the
ways it can go wrong then you're like
okay what what am I going to do in the
AGI world and you get kind of like
ambiguous
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah these like ambiguous answers that
are like, well, you know,
it'll be a a beautiful world.
>> I actually before we move on
>> Or go ahead.
>> I want
I want to say
>> a hot take.
>> Uh open invite to open AI, Anthropic,
>> SpaceX, I guess. I don't really use
those models. Thinking Machines,
>> uh to come on to the show and be
specific about how the world gets
better. Specifics. None of this woo-woo
like we will take over labor and you
will uh uh like uh food and health and
energy will be solved. No, like please
come on to the show and give us 10
minutes of best-case scenarios with as
specific as you can get. I will
>> I would love that.
>> I will pay 20 more dollars for that. I
don't mind using money for [laughter]
that. I'm just
>> Huge budget over here.
>> Just saying, okay? I would like just
come on and like I and uh like like like
the three of us aren't Well, it doesn't
really matter to us uh and I assume
there are way more high-profile podcasts
or events they can go to, but I promise
you I will be your biggest fan if you
can come here and be specific about it.
I'm like just just come on. It's fine.
It'll be good.
>> I would mention like in the short term,
I have like enjoy like I I'm very happy
excited these technologies exist.
>> Yep.
>> Like I I very much see the upside in
them. Was it the ability to like your
ability to jump into like a new code
base now and like stop being immediately
like productive in it is like pretty
incredible. They're not quite there yet,
but it's more like uh hooking them up to
things, but like
the ability for it to go synthesize a
bunch of information out of all of your
like positive models or like
>> Yep.
>> There's
Yeah. It's really nice.
>> for everyone listening, I may have to
step away here briefly because I was
using
Codex's computer use
skill or MCP, which is very very good.
And if you haven't used it, please try
it out cuz it is like remarkably
amazing, but I have a package showing up
likely during the recording of this that
I did not plan for. I had asked Codex to
go research what the cost or process to
order a new Apple remote for Apple TV
was, and it actually went through the
whole flow, and because I was logged
into one password and have my credit
card in one password, it did the full
checkout, and I got a text this morning
that I have a package arriving during
the time frame of this recording. So, if
I have to go sign for that, apologize.
But yeah, check out check out computer
use. It's very good.
>> I'm surprised we haven't seen more
like accessibility cool outs about
computer use. I might my assumption is
that it would be a big benefit there,
but maybe there's like already good
systems in place
for that. But yeah.
>> If OpenAI gets their teams to like
collaborate, I assume the plan is to get
ChatGPT Codex to like take over the
computer. Like they finally like have
the technology, but they need to get all
300 teams to point in the same direction
to do it. I think that's what they want
to do.
>> It is remarkably good. I use it now for
like a lot of testing, like letting the
agent test stuff using computer use, and
it is uh
it's very good. I'm excited for it to be
faster and more reliable. I almost want
like a code mode API around computer
use.
>> I'm surprised this is this is where I'm
at with my testing stuff. Where I
actually don't want to use computer use
for testing because you can't like
codify Codex's computer use into like
end-to-end tests in your repo.
And so you can more you can have like a
you can instead of having it use
computer use, you can just have it drive
like Playwright, and then test against
whatever you use, which is pretty nice.
>> So, wait. Well, we'll
we'll save that for maybe
our next episode for going through your
workflow. But moving on to the next
topic, the thing I wanted to talk about
before we dive into my workflow,
And we still have to get through Suno's
hot take on
conferences. Is I am really really
excited about Thinking Machines and
[music] Inkling and American open source
open weight models. So for anyone that
doesn't know, Mira Murati, hopefully I'm
getting her name right. I believe she
was the former CTO of OpenAI. She spun
off and created her own company called
Thinking Machines and in the past week
they released their first model called
Inkling and it is open weight open
source and the write-up and release
around this was phenomenal. Their
benchmarks were incredibly transparent.
I think they got a lot of praise across
Twitter for the way they demonstrated
the capabilities
of this model.
And one thing that is
insanely cool and distinctly unique
about Inkling is they shipped
tools or a harness. I'm not sure which.
I haven't I only read over the the blog
briefly, but they shipped tooling to
essentially RL and fine-tune the model
in your own hands. And the demo or the
the demo they give is in an open code
session. They they load up Inkling and
they run the you know slash post train
or whatever the command is. I can't
recall. And say basically stop
outputting words with the letter E in it
and it runs this whole skill and updates
the weights and biases or you know, I
don't fully understand the full you know
post training process, but
it updates itself similar to like
something like Pi.
And then it showed an example of them
talking back and forth with the model
and
sure enough the letter E doesn't show up
anywhere. And like I think that's
fascinating and insanely cool. Uh like I
like thinking of use cases. Like I I use
my an agent to like budget. And like if
I could fine-tune it to like nail down
and be really, really good at using the
tools and the knowledge around how I'm
to do my ball
budget, excuse me. Um
I think that would be insane. Um so I'm
curious on your guys' take on this. And
like my the other part of this is there
was a good tweet from Xiaoyan Zhu
saying, "My bet is Thinking Machines
will soon make more money than Anthropic
AI. Not by winning the race to build one
standardized frontier model, by becoming
the Palantir forward-deployed engineer
for enterprise custom models. The
playbook: One, release the best American
open-weight model. Two, drive widespread
enterprise adoption. Three, charge the
largest companies seven to nine figures
to post-train and run custom models
behind their own firewall.
The model rests on three bets. Large
enterprises will increasingly demand
their own models with their own data,
and this is how they differentiate and
win. Enterprises won't need just one
model. They'll continuously need new
models for different workflows,
departments, and proprietary data sets.
That creates extremely sticky recurring
revenue. Three, auto research will make
custom model development increasingly
scalable. Tinker can become the
interface enterprises use to post-train
their models with Thinking Machines
providing the expertise and
infrastructure behind it.
Forward-deployed engineers, infra
everything, huge contracts.
Four, eventually maybe everyone wants
their own model and auto research and
training inside Tinker, which Tinker
must be the tooling that they have to
post-train this. And auto research and
training inside Tinker on top of
Thinking Machines base model will make
it happen.
>> [snorts]
>> Meanwhile, Henry Ford-styled
standardized models will make no
margins. OpenAI and Anthropic will have
their API margin squeezed by DeepSeek,
JLM, Grok, Meta, etc. And their consumer
subscriptions are loss centers already.
The fat margin will move to
customization, proprietary data,
post-training evals, deployment, and
infrastructure. If this thesis is right,
Think Machines isn't building just
another frontier lab, it's building the
highest value layer between frontier
research and enterprise model ownership.
Turns out the best
the best business model for enterprise
is not to sell commodity API access,
sell them their own model.
I'm extremely bullish on this approach.
Mira Murati may be the most commercially
savvy frontier lab leader, I have to
admit it, and I actually
completely agree with this tweet. I
think
that this is partially aligns with like
Cloudflare's bet on Workers AI and
hosting and running open weight models.
Um I think that both Anthropic and
OpenAI have
got themselves into financial positions
that
are going to be increasingly hard to
deliver returns to their investors on,
and a model like this could really,
really disrupt the two big labs. So,
curious on uh
how you guys felt about this.
>> Uh I I have two thoughts. First of all,
I don't know if you know, I am a Mira
Murati stan like from the beginning.
Holy extremely accomplished, knows
how to get work done, like big-time
Murati fan. The second is a week ago
from today, so on the 10th of July, they
published their internal manifesto thing
called The Future Worth Building is
Human, where they actually go over these
details, and it's a remarkable document
for two reasons.
These manifestos are usually very
surface-level,
very, very solar-punk future-looking,
but this actually like goes into
specifics into some of like even the
writings that have influenced them. Like
they talk They have like a Hayek
uh document written in like 1945 about
like the use of knowledge in society. I
highly recommend anyone uh who's
watching this to find the link in uh uh
the notes for this episode and read it.
And they go into the details about this
because they say we are pursuing these
directions. We train strong models. We
build tools that enable people to make
AI their own. We develop interfaces and
we publish research. Uh which is a
remarkable thing for also a company
that's raised billions of dollars to say
that this is the direction that they're
going in. It's uh
um
I'm I'm a fan. Uh and the third thing
which is just a bonus thing is Thinking
Machines would have been too long for
the Twitter handle which is why that
Twitter handle is Thinking Machines
which is the cutest thing I've ever seen
in my life. I I I love it.
>> Race, do you think this puts Anthropic
and OpenAI kind of in the hot seat?
>> I don't know. I feel like it maybe gets
I I think I'm maybe a little bearish on
it in that I feel like it maybe gets
better lessened away.
>> What do you mean by that?
>> In that like there's
you know how as the models get better,
you like can get rid of your
like certain like guiding skills or
whatnot. Like they stop like doing
certain anti-patterns
uh just as the nature of like putting
more compute into them and uh scaling
them up.
Um
>> [clears throat]
>> I feel like we've kind of seen like
micro-optimizations
matter a bit less. But then I At the
same time, I think there was some stuff
from RAMP that showed that they like
were able to fine-tune fine-tune models
and get uh like better and cheaper
results out of them. Um so I think it's
it's like cool to exist. I maybe just
don't relate as much to like the um
space that it exists in at the moment.
Like for me I feel like for the
budgeting one, I would rather do like I
would rather codify that as a set of
skills and instructions so that I can
like swap out the model as I need than
like a fine-tuned model.
>> Why Why both if it's effectively pennies
or cheap?
>> Um
>> Which I think is like the enterprise use
case. Like so much of our workloads at
Cloudflare that are not like individuals
using coding agents. Like many of our
automated business processes are running
on open weight
models.
>> But do you need fine-tuning for this?
>> I think that we could achieve
likely better results
>> Better results.
>> increase efficiency, both better
outcomes for our users of those products
and better outcomes financially for us.
Um which I think matters as well.
>> Yeah, that makes sense. That makes
sense, yeah.
Do you think the best
And this is just a completely random
country. Okay, so the country of
Kazakhstan.
Do you think a model will be able to
from first principles derive the best
way to run civic processes, etc. in
Kazakhstan? Because I don't I suspect
most of that knowledge is not openly
available. And I don't think they could
be easily condensed into simple skills
that you can fit in a context window.
Do you see what like the whole
fine-tuning thing is that you can chuck
a whole bunch of data at it and get it
tuned to your use case.
So for example, the
I've been having a theory recently that
you know like Claude wise and open AI
wise, you know, not just M dashes, but
the X not Y etc. thing.
>> Yeah.
>> Those are not problems that can be
solved by just like skills, right? Like
and the other thing I was I don't know
if we mentioned it in the last call,
which is I don't want to hire five
different Clauds for a team. Like uh
>> Yep.
>> Uh Miami 5-0 was not made of five uh Mr.
T characters. Like they're like
different You want to like have like
different models that can like interact
with each others and they're not just
the same model but with skills. So
there's something there and it's a short
worth taking. I guess that's what I'm
saying. Like uh
I would bet
>> Oh yeah, I fully agree. It's like,
well worth exploring. Um Um
Yeah, I mean, just to see how it works
out.
>> Sweet. Well, this is definitely
something I want to keep kind of our
finger on the pulse of, especially
around finicky machines, and see where
this goes, because I I'm I'm personally
very excited about it.
And I do think it does put Anthropic and
OpenAI in a pretty in a much harder
position given their financial positions
and, you know, the returns they have to
do, the revenue they have to make to
satisfy, you know, data center build-out
and obligations to companies like
Oracle.
So,
we'll we'll keep a pulse on that over
the the coming months. Before we The
last topic to get into before we dive
into my workflow and how I work with AI
every day is, Sunil, you not only
recently attended AI World Fair with us,
but you also
attended a local
>> First Conf.
>> So, we were on the Expo floor of AI
Engineer World's Fair, 7,000 people, 10
parallel tracks, workshops,
taking over all of Moscone, what have
you. And I did that. I spent a week in
New York, where I went to the new
Cloudflare office. I went to John's of
Bleecker Street to get pizza. I love it.
I've heard it's a top five pizza of the
world. And of course, I bought the
merch. I buy the merch everywhere.
And then I went to Berlin. Beautiful
city, by the way, especially if you like
it's made for cyclists, so you can have
like two beers, get a buzz on, and just
like cycle through the city. Amazing
feeling. I don't recommend it.
Sorry, younger people. Oh, it's so bad.
You should not get drunk and ride a
cycle through a beautiful city. Don't do
that.
Um
uh but Local First Conf is It was
wonderful, because I I to say it was
like 300, maybe 350 people, maybe less
actually. I don't know.
Uh but bunch of research nerds, people
like from Ink & Switch, Jazz Tools, who
are
talking about data sovereignty,
owning your stack, and not having a big
tech influence, which is funny because
Cloudflare was sponsoring it, and it did
get a few people on Blue Sky mad about
that. And I don't really I did catch
that. I just like whatever, you know.
I get mad about it on Twitter later.
It's fine.
But
it did strike me
about
where change happens and
how do I put this? I met Dan Ingalls,
one of the creators of object-oriented
programming at Local First Conf. Like I
don't think the organizers knew
beforehand that he was coming, and he
was just like a dude in a t-shirt and
shorts sitting around. Like I saw his
badge. I was like, wait, there can't be
like two Dan Ingalls in the world.
Um
and it like
a conference like AI Engineer World's
Fair must exist. It's surely a sign that
something is going right, and Sean Wang
has built like this generational
conference.
Um
but I think if you want to be closer in
the know of the people like doing the
work,
I've managed to interact with
and I'm saying this is worth the 7,000
people. I did enjoy my time at Local
First Conf, and I met a lot more
interesting people there non-stop over
the 3 days of the conference.
I don't really have a point here to
make, I guess. It was just
it was just very strange to me that
this happened. I guess
it's kind of why our podcast exists in
the first place. Like we are three
practitioners, and we are tired of
hearing like hypemen and people selling
things all the time,
which is why I want to see how Dylan
like literally types on his keyboard,
you know? Like that's that's the thing
that like interests me. I'm I'm not
interested in your AI agent framework. I
want to see a dude like punch his
keyboard and generate code.
>> Well, I have bad news for you. I've been
using a lot of dictation
to drive agents. But this is actually
I think it's encouraging to me cuz I I
think at least
you and I talked a bit
when we were sitting at the the pub
after we recorded our last podcast, but
I personally feel like I didn't get a
ton out of AI world fair, and I think
that was a combination of one just like
we've been going
I I feel pretty confident saying the
three of us have put a lot of time and
effort and care into figuring out how to
use
this tech, and I think
maybe a a large portion of the talks at
AI engineer were kind of maybe higher
level, kind of more hype driven, or just
stuff that like
I haven't found to work thus far. So,
it's it
it's encouraging to me to hear that like
there is progress being pushed in the
other niches of engineering like local
first technology, and that the you know,
the bar and the needle is still moving
even if it's
uh drowned out in my Twitter algorithm,
and I'm not currently seeing stuff like
that. So, I'm that makes me relieved to
hear. Reese, any any thoughts before we
look at how I produce slop on a daily
basis?
>> Uh no, I'm let's jump into the slop
cannon.
>> [music]
>> Okay, so transitioning to the segment
that many of y'all have been waiting for
and asking for. This will be the first
of at least three
episodes or segments where Reese and I
go over how we're working with AI on a
day-to-day basis in real uh code bases
with real, you know, users.
Um and I want to kind of start by
talking about my tooling, kind of where
I came from, where I'm at right now as
far as tooling, and then I can walk
through a example of a feature I shipped
to
um Hurder, which we'll talk about here
in a second, in the past week. And also,
coincidentally, how my workflow uh since
I recorded, or not recorded, but ran
through implementing this the first time
till today has already started to change
a little bit. Um
So,
I have been living in the terminal for
basically the bath the past
14 years. I've been using
uh tmux since 2014. I abandoned VS Code
sometime around 2019, 2020, and jumped
into the Neovim world.
Uh
and that was mostly because of actually
RSI pain. So, uh my my workflow has been
largely geared around the terminal and
tmux for the better part of my career.
And up until Opus 4.5, I was not very
AI-pilled. I was using Claude Code a
little bit. Then, like many people, I
used Opus 4.5 and realized very quickly
that uh the technology changed and
agentic engineering was going to uh be
the future of where this was all going.
And, you know, I had a existential
dilemma over the holidays, I think like
many many people had, had some like
restless nights about figuring out like
what
what does my job mean? I've been
programming since I was 11 years old,
uh reading code articles daily. Um like,
what does it mean for me to be a
software engineer when being a software
engineer
uh is so much of my identity, for better
or worse. And
um um
you know, took a lot of time to get
where I'm at today. And I think that's
probably one thing that's not talked
about enough is that
this is like a completely new skill set.
Like I don't think you can go from the
workflows we were doing
in the past to agentic engineering and
getting good results off the rip. I I
don't think when the models are there, I
don't think the toolings are there or
the tooling is there. And it it's
still incredibly hard. And the thing
that, you know, I think we've talked
about a little bit, but like it is
exhausting to work
in this way with this technology despite
it actually
sometimes annoyingly uh making me
generally more productive. So, bearing
in mind that I've been in the terminal
forever. I am I've had a, you know, a
pull towards using the terminal-based
agent harnesses. So, I started with
Claude Code in October. Uh and last year
I was using Claude, you know, on the
side, like I mentioned, but then really
went full-time into Claude Code through
the holidays and into like, you know,
January, February. And then I had
switched to using Open Code for a month
or two. And then I found Py. So, that's
probably the first
important thing uh to in my current
tooling
is Py. That is the agent harness I use
every day. And it is
uh Anyone that doesn't know, Py is made
by our good friend uh Mario, friend of
the pod, uh at Arendelle. And it is
advertised as a one
shitty coding agent. But more
importantly, uh it is advertised as a uh
minimalistic coding agent. And so, like
what does that really mean in practice?
Um yeah, here's the the the copy. Here's
the website. We'll link it in the show
notes, but Pi, there are many agent
harnesses, but this one is yours. Pi is
a minimal agent harness. Adapt Pi to
your workflows, not the other way
around.
So,
Pi has a incredibly minimal system
prompt. I mean, it is like
a paragraph or two,
a couple outlines of the tools it has,
and that is it. Like, it is probably,
you know, under
certainly under 2K tokens, probably
under 1K.
Um, and when I first used Pi,
this is all based on vibes, but I think
there are there are benchmarks out there
that show
similar results, but like I could feel
immediately a difference between using
Pi and something like Open Code, which
at the time, I don't know if this is
still the case with Open Code, but I
believe Open Code at the time was based
on your model, it was trying to emulate
the system prompt of like, you know,
Codex or Claude Code when you switched
models.
This is just static. There's like four
tools, you know, read, write, bash.
It doesn't even have web search or web
fetch tools. And you could feel off the
rip that like to me it it felt more
focused and more likely to do what I was
asking with better results, even like
with models like Opus 4.5 and or like
Kimmy K2.
Um,
and I I I attribute that to the minimal
context that's going into it. And
importantly,
the team behind Pi does not make updates
to
the harness very often, and I find that
very important.
In a time where these models are very
dynamic and stochastic and
non-deterministic,
I don't want
the other parts of my tooling regularly
changing behavior underneath of me
because that makes it harder for me to
find a stable workflow with consistent
results.
And Pie really I think has helped me get
to a place where I can get a stable
workflow.
The other remarkably cool thing about
Pie which you've I believe that amp has
now cribbed and open code is also
working on I think for their two dot o
release is Pie out of the box knows how
to modify itself. So it has one of the
most beautiful plugin systems I've ever
seen. So you can basically load up a Pie
session and say, "Hey, I I I want you to
build a MCP tool." And it will go read
its docs. It has very clear instructions
on its APIs, where its source code is,
and how to basically extend itself. So
it's
super easy to model Pie
around your workflow.
One cool thing that I saw recently was
from Ben Vinegar from Modum. He was
talking about how he built
he shaped a custom harness with Pie
around his workflow for
editing
his podcast. Like he basically built
extensions tooling, you know, whatever
it is with Pie so like he could load up
into it and it was specifically shaped
for his workflow around doing that
particular task. So that that's one
reason why I love Pie. It's great.
I have a
handful of extensions.
I don't use very many admittedly.
There's like an extension market that
you can go to and install stuff. But my
would my advice to anyone trying Pie
would be use it out of the box and don't
add extensions until you start to feel
pain.
And then when you do feel pain, take a
look at the extensions that are publicly
available and decide if that fits you
well. And if it does, install it. If it
doesn't, use them as inspiration and
then tell Pi to build something like it
that is more equipped to you because
it just works. So, the extensions I use
is I have a custom gateway that I use at
work
that we use through
Cloudflare gateway. I have a
Pi cloak extension, which basically just
masks environment variables if they
somehow get into the session. A Pi skill
toggle, which basically turns skills on
and off for letting the agent invoke
skills or making me
invoke skills. I have an extension for
saving markdown, so I can do  MD
and that will save the last agent
message to a markdown file. I have my
web tools extension, which is basically
a port of open codes web search and what
that tools.
Um
I have an answer tool, which I don't
ever use anymore. I can probably get rid
of this.
Uh if the agent compacts, which it
really does, this just continues it.
Uh a get I get AI integration, a get
interceptor, which I think is quite
funny. Uh
This basically will block the agent if
it tries to use no verify cuz I use a
lot of like linting rules with like ox
lint or like AST grep. Uh so, if the
agent tries to use no verify in a bash
command, it spits out no verify is not
allowed. Good get hooks exist for a
reason. Do not attempt to bypass them.
Instead, fix the underlying issue that
is causing the hook to fail or ask the
user for help.
Um
So, just like very minimal. Like, I
don't have a lot of extra here.
These are just some like kind of quality
of life things that I added.
Then I have an MCP tool I also built.
So, that is like the extent of my my Pi
agent. And you can see here like this is
all it is. Um nothing super fancy. And
then I also have been
using Matt Pocock's
uh uh
engineering skills quite a bit, uh which
we'll get into a bit.
The other second important tool in my
uh tool chain is Herder,
uh which this is what is kind of
encapsulating or wrapping around my Pi
session here. That is what the sidebar
on the side is. Um these different
workspaces, these different agents
running. So, Herder is a lot like uh
Tmux, but
for the age of agents. And as I
mentioned at the top of the show, I've
been using Tmux since 2014. I've been
dragging my Tmux config along with me
for a long time.
And
I was really skeptical of Herder when I
first used it. I admittedly have been
waiting for Mitchell Hashimoto to finish
his conquest of getting rid of terminal
multiplexers through uh Ghosty, uh but
that's not here yet. But, the next best
thing is that Herder is built on lib
Ghosty. So, this actually ended up
solving a bunch of my pain points with
Tmux, which is things like uh ANSI
escape sequences not supporting Kitty
image protocol. Like, there's just a lot
of weird things that make Tmux not
optimal when working with like a modern
uh terminal like Ghosty or Kitty or, you
know, whatever else. I was able to
basically convert all of my bindings
from Tmux to Herder in one shot, and now
I have basically this working product,
and some cool things about Herder is
that it has agent tracking and like
their support. So, I could like come in
here and be like review the code, right?
And you'll see when I run that, it kicks
off. So, I can see a status of like if
it's blocked, if it's running, what's
going on. Um
which I love, uh which I didn't have
with Tmux. When I was running Tmux, I
was like using sound notifications to
like grab my attention back when agents
finished, and that was you know, kind of
chaotic.
>> Did Did you convert the bindings or did
uh
>> Oh, yeah. I I literally just told GPT to
uh set up Herder and copy all of my key
bindings and settings over to Herder,
and it basically just like one shot it,
and I
>> I think that that's a fun quick cool out
of like the cost of adopting new tools
has never been Yeah. Lower. And so, like
you really get to experiment with what
makes the best workflow for you.
>> Yeah. I I love it a ton.
Um
And then other than that, uh another
important tool is
uh Planotator, which is a tool that
launches a local web app that lets you
basically
review
files.
Uh it lets you do local code review, and
it lets you kind of like annotate files,
code review, or even like the previous
agent message, and send those results
right back into the coding agent. We'll
dive into that here in a couple minutes.
I'll give it like a real example of how
that works. But that's been a really
important tool. And then I find myself
very rarely diving into my code editor,
which is Neovim, uh anymore, which is
quite sad. But uh from time to time when
I do need to do manual editing, I'm
using Neovim. So, that's basically like
my full
tool stack at the moment.
So, to
give an example of something I built in
my actual workflow here. I started
working on a feature for Herder. So,
when you create a new tab in Herder, I
can come in here, I can create a new
tab. And when I create a new tab, it,
you know, it will ask me to name the
tab. So, if I do like Fubar, it's going
to name it Fubar up there, right? So, I
can also come in here and create a new
workspace. However, when I create a new
workspace, it does not let me give me
the option to rename it. It just kind of
adopts the current directory and then I
have to do this second step where I have
to, you know, rename it over here. Now
it's foobarbat, right? So I wanted to
basically add the feature where when I
create a new workspace, I can get that
same modal to name it before it opens.
Let me uh grab the session here.
If we do pi dash resume.
Right here. Oh, that's still not the
right one.
Pi dash resume.
So a uh one thing you'll see in here is
pi has this feature called tree, which
is probably like the most sticky feature
of pi for me uh beyond the things I've
already talked about. Tree lets you jump
around any point of the conversation. Uh
so like you can go down some path. Let's
say I want to write unit tests for a
feature. I can like go build that out
and then I can jump back to the root of
the conversation and like you can choose
when you jump to another point in the
conversation, you can choose to
summarize it, summarize it with a custom
prompt, no summary, or just jump back
and forth. This is almost like doing
manual sub agents,
uh which I'll demonstrate here in a
second, but like I literally cannot live
without this feature in a
uh coding agent uh anymore. It's
probably
probably the most important feature
feature of pi to me.
>> Does slash tree come with pi or did you
add it with an extension?
>> Slash tree is built natively into pi.
All right. So where I started here was
I started by and I forget the the exact
name of this strategy, but I will often
start work with an agent by
asking it questions that
I either know the answer to or I myself
need the answer to, but I'll I'll start
with asking questions, right? So, I
asked, "How does the feature work for
Herder where when creating a new tab in
a space a user can be prompted to name
it first? What is the code path? How's
the abstraction designed? How's the
config value to enable/disable
that feature read and parsed and passed
to the create tab flow/feature?"
So, if we jump through the conversation
here, we can see that
it ended up coming out here with this
basically overview of how this feature
works, right? And in fact, this is a big
blob of text that is really hard to just
like read in the terminal. So, this is a
great example of like a place where I
will use Planetator. So, I'll do
Planetator last. And what this will do
is it's going to launch a web app where
it will load the last agent's message
into a web app right here, and I can go
through and read it. And I can, you
know, it just makes it easier to digest.
And on top of that, I can come in here
and I can be like, you know, "Are you
sure about this?
Can you be more clear?"
Right? Something like this, right? Just
this is just a throwaway example, and I
can save that, and it basically
aggregates these comments as I go
through.
And then I can if I were to click send
feedback, which I'll show in a second,
this would send all of this back into my
session and let the answer or let the
agent respond.
So,
here my intent was to basically have it
go off and do research, almost like a
sub-agent would, right? Like I'm being
my own sub-agent. My I have a hot take
that I think
sub-agents
autonomous sub-agents in coding
harnesses have a tendency to
take thinking away from the developer
too easily. So, I like kind of doing
this this thing on my own, and I I don't
want to defer
the prompts and the context gathering to
another agent
orchestrating a sub-agent. Like I want
to be in control of that.
So, you know, we can click send
feedback. It will send it and you can
see here
uh
it sent the message in a message message
feedback and it would go address that.
So,
I will oftentimes like go back and forth
with agents planning work this way,
asking questions, gathering context. Um
but in this case, I was pretty happy
with uh the outcome of this. I felt, you
know, this feels like enough information
about how this feature works. So, then I
ended up doing tree and I jumped back to
zero context and I uh started a new
thread in the same session, right? I'm
now back to 0% context and then I was
like, how does the create new workspace
feature abstractions code path
configuration types and data paths work
for Herder?
And I let that run off and eventually it
resolved um to
Let me find my labels here.
Create workspace research. You can also
label anywhere in the conversation and
jump around them.
So, here it came out with the same thing
and we can go look at this in Planitator
again
and it outlines how the current create
workspace feature is, which is the thing
I want to change, right?
So, here's this nice very succinct uh
compact way that this works.
So, again, I was happy with that outcome
and now I jumped back to uh
I jumped back to 0% context and actually
here uh I used the save markdown skill
and I wrote this last message to a
markdown file, which you can see is
right here. This is exactly what we just
looked like, saved it to a markdown
file.
So, I jumped back and then we jumped to
and I say uh
open this in Neovim.
You can see I have rarely used my editor
cuz I have a bunch of updates.
Um,
I asked read at create workspace MD,
which is the file I just made from that
last branch, to learn how workspace
creation works in Hurder. Here is how
tab creation plus renaming works and I
just copy and pasted that first branch
where we got the summary of how the tab
rename works. I copy and pasted that
into just like a details tab.
And then down at the bottom I said,
uh, I closed the details, right? I
I don't know. This is all vibes putting
it inside those like tags, but just
trying to like distinguish the different
signal there. I said, "How would you add
design and implement the feature
capability to Hurder for introducing a
similar feature to tabs with a new
configuration option so that when you
create a new workspace, you're given the
option to name the workspace at creation
time. Walk me through the code paths,
data structures you would create, update
or change, the types you would add,
change, delete, anything relevant like
that."
I really want you to focus on code
paths, types, abstractions, and data
flow.
I do this thing when I'm planning with
agents where
rather than having these kind of
high-level uh, almost like PRD product
docs, I like my specs looking more like
pseudo code and I focus on having the
agent outline types. I basically do
type-driven development uh, with the
agent. So, my my specs end up looking
like an outline of code and I also do
this thing that's gotten some attention
on Twitter where I have it like outline
the call stack uh, of like what the
agent plans what the call stack is today
uh, and how it wants to change it. And
at each level of the call stack I ask it
to say, "What is the input type? What is
the output type? What are any side
effects that can occur and what are any
errors that can occur?" And I make it
just outline that. And that I I find, at
least on a vibe basis, that that really
helps keep the agents on track and stay
aligned with like my expectation of like
abstractions.
So, I ran that off, and it ended up
coming out with uh
the initial spec.
And you can see here we have this
document, and I have that loaded into
Neovim, which in fact we should just
look at in planetator.
Right, so let's say planetator, and we
can use annotate, and here I can mark
any file. Uh and I think this is yeah,
create a namespace spec.
So, if you look at the spec in here, you
close this, we have
you know, this outline of code paths
focusing on types already.
Um you know, I'm not going to walk
through this all line by line here, but
you can see that there's like a real
emphasis on code and types here rather
than just like
you know, as a user I want to do XYZ.
And it also outlines uh I have it
outlined like red green refactor tests,
and doing like a much inspired from Matt
Pocock's skills, like vertical slices.
Like, what is the narrowest
part of this feature that you could
implement that proves it end to end, and
then let's add to that over time.
>> What that note on terminal control in
the planning.com from?
>> Uh where was it?
>> Point 11. It mentions uh testing in
terminal control. It's uh up a little
bit. I'm going curious that's coming
from agent MD or from you.
>> I after it produced that spec and I read
through it, I uh I have a skill for
terminal control, and I said add
verification and proof with terminal
control to our spec so that a human can
verify the correctness of your
implementation. So, that was me after
the first spec came out.
Uh Sunu, you you had a question.
>> So,
I the the idea of having it almost like
generate types and then having it like
fill in the blanks is very appealing.
But, the question is like why? Have you
noticed Is it because you feel strongly
that the function boundary should be
defined by you? Or are you saying that
models are still not good enough at
generating those boundaries? Or you
noticed just like
I want to understand like why you do it
this way. It is very appealing by the
way. Like I And the reason I'm asking is
like does it scale?
>> Yeah. I do it because one, that's almost
how I worked
previous to AI. I always started
at the type level and thought about
types and interfaces first. And, you
know, when I used to create a new
JavaScript module or file, like I tried
to keep a single module
centered around a single core type and
then build functions and combinators
around that type. And if I feel myself
starting to operate over different
types, that's probably a a good sign
that I need to break out to a new
module. And I kind of compose those
together. And I definitely do not think
that agents are good enough or the
models today are good enough at doing uh
like abstraction and system design. Uh
they
even with
guidance and skills and everything, they
still
quite frankly produce really bad slop.
So, this gives me
the ability up front to align on
how the system is going to fit together
and how data is going to flow through
it. And like looking at a call stack, I
can like very clearly see how data will
flow through it. and it it because, you
know, it's
so much code is coming out and I mean I
still read all the code in review, but
like this also helps cement my
understanding of the abstractions and
how data and code flows through through
my services that I'm working on.
>> I've never seen a model go, "Oh, this
file is getting too big. I need to
refactor it."
>> Yeah, [laughter] exactly.
>> Like
they don't they don't feel the friction
in the way that they feel. I really like
this flow. This is great.
>> They also do this thing where like
they make tons of tiny abstractions.
Like I can give them uh Matt Pocock's
skill and like deep modules, for
example, which I think is very useful
and I still use and
will inject into the context for some of
this, but it will like make these very
thin interfaces and create just like
one-off adapters and it's just like
I want you to
look at the abstractions we currently
have. I want you to look at the
interfaces we already have. Does it fit
anywhere? Can we adapt any of them? Is
something wrong? Uh rather than just
being so trigger-happy to make a new
abstraction. So, I've been trying to
like put resistance between introducing
new abstractions with the agent, if that
makes sense.
>> The other thing I really love is this
plan editor is incredible and I regret
not trying it even though you've told me
like 10 times to do it because the UX
model of just being able to like paint
like just brush strokes over areas and
like comment on it and then pass it on
is very different from this idea of the
entire source code be behind a chat
window and the chat being the only thing
that you interact with. How has every
other agentic AI ID not stolen this
year? This is just absolutely remarkable
UX. I love it.
>> Codex just in the past couple days
introduced the ability to like annotate
the previous agent message and send
feedback in. So, like
>> [gasps]
>> I actually like a lot of times I will
not settle on the first output of a
plan, right? I'll come in here and be
like, I don't like the name of this
type. You're like, this should be
this should be workspace
name action instead.
And then I'll come down here and be
like,
you know,
this is wrong, you know, back and forth
and then I'll have it update the spec
and then I'll launch back in and just go
back and forth using plan annotator like
this because I can
make these larger brush strokes to the
full plan rather than being like having
to scroll up and down in my terminal and
like copy and paste pieces and like
aggregate that together in a tiny text
box. It's It's so useful. Plan annotator
has been without a doubt the most
important tool, I think, to like getting
good outcomes.
>> I feel like it would also cool out that
this is is probably not how the labs the
like
labs want you to be working with the
models. Like
like that's why
like that's why the like interfaces
aren't designed like this and that like
they don't they
I think that they probably want you to
be deferring more to the models and like
trying to solve these problems through
like loops rather than
>> How do you square that with Codex
adopting the ability to
or annotate the previous agent message
now?
>> That it's like nowhere near the same.
I think it's like a
parallel feature. It's not like
trying to solve the same. Do you know
what I mean?
>> Interesting.
>> Like it's it's more for like
highlighting a bit of text than it is uh
>> Like planning and doing work.
>> Yeah.
I I would say this is maybe more for
like Claude than it is for OpenAI, I I
would say on like Claude desktop.
>> I haven't used Claude or any of that
stuff for so long that I I I can't
comment on I don't I just don't know
whether what the state of the art is
currently.
Beyond pushing loops and dynamic
workflows and stuff.
>> But it was I think that this is a better
flow than like the loops and dynamic
workflows. I know it's it's so
interesting how much uh
how how much the way how many different
ways of working have evolved over the
past 3 years.
>> Yeah.
>> Like you have this you have
whatever the hell the bun rewrite was
which is like incredible.
>> Oh, we've got dogs barking.
>> [laughter]
>> That might be the delivery of
uh
>> of your Codex Apple TV remote.
>> Yeah, I might have to step away for yep,
I'll be right back.
New Apple remote courtesy of
>> courtesy of Codex.
>> Codex, is this now an unboxing stream?
Is that what we're doing?
>> Um
>> See it.
Oh, dude, this is
>> Hey, Ollie.
I need to set I want to set up Codex
computer used to just order groceries
for me automatically.
>> Dude, I'm telling you it auto ordered an
Apple remote for me and I didn't even
know it.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you, Codex.
>> I guess I could just give it its own
credit card.
>> I'm still stunned by the Plan out data
UX because now I'm thinking about how it
would generalize for like like regular
life use cases.
Like it doesn't know just for coding
agents, right?
>> I use it when I'm budgeting. Like it'll
put out like I'll be like how can I
recon reconcile like my Amex and I'll
like it outline like what it thinks how
to square, you know, transactions to
different budget categories and I'll
just launch that in the Plan out data
and I'll correct it where it needs to
and then it'll go do go through executor
with the YNAB MCP generated by the open
API spec and just do it. Yeah, it's
fantastic. So, I want to show you
another feature of Plan out data which
is its local code review capabilities.
And this is something that I like really
hyper-focused on early in the year. Like
I was tweeting about it a lot. I was
generating prototypes. Um I I felt very
early on that local code review
was an issue. Like I did not want to
push code to GitLab or GitHub and have
it public yet. Like I didn't feel like
that flow was good for reviewing code. I
didn't want like co-workers to have to
get notifications for pushes that
weren't ready yet. So, I was really like
trying to find a solution and
Planetator was that. So, once I have the
spec finished, right? We have our spec
file here. It has all the stuff
outlined. It has
the types, the code, blah blah blah.
Um validation, verification, tests,
everything. So, once I kick this off and
it goes through implementing it, I will
let it run, let it finish, let it do its
first pass over to anything. I currently
have been experimenting with a skill uh
my own skill for doing code review that
um
I have a skill for my own coding
standards. Basically, it's like a
two-track It actually uses Matt Pocock's
skill for kind of two-track comparison.
One, it checks one sub-agent will check
against the spec. One sub-agent will
check against my coding standards and
then do an initial pass.
I've found that like I'm spending more
time than I want doing code review and
constantly have to like nitpick the same
thing. So, I'm just trying I've been
experimenting with how to get a good
first pass over that.
But, once the code's done, you we can
come in here and do something like
Planetator review.
And this will launch up and if you diff
it against origin/main, you can come in
here and kind of see basically all the
changes. And then I'll come through here
and this is where I this is how I still
read all of the code, right? Like I'll
come in here and I will read the diffs.
And let's say I don't like this. Like I
do it, you know, X, Y, and Z.
Add comment, you know,
just step through file through file, and
this is all built on PR diffs, so it's
lovely diffing.
And you can basically just step through
everything, see it, and then you can
send feedback. And that will feed back
into the agent code review feedback, and
then it will go uh address it and fix
it. And then I basically just repeat
this process
until I'm happy with it.
So, that that's basically like where my
workflow has been at for the past 2
months. It gets pretty close to
producing code that I would have written
myself before AI and agentic engineering
was here. And I'm able to work on two or
three features, whether that's in work
trees or several projects kind of at
once and jump back and forth on while
the agents are reviewing or writing
code. It is way more exhausting, I
think, than before, but I am more
productive, and that's how I'm getting
good outcomes.
Um one thing I do want to talk about
quick is I mentioned at the start of uh
me talking about my workflow that I've
started to experiment with Matt Pocock
skills a little bit more, and in
particular leaning into his kind of
wayfinder workflow, which if anyone's
familiar with uh his grill me and grill
me with docs, which have been quite
popular,
um those two skills basically help you
align with the agent on like what you're
actually trying to build or solve. It
will like kind of relentlessly interview
you and go down every path. And he built
on top of that to build this thing
called wayfinder, which is for bigger
work that might take
multiple planning sessions.
Um and this will outline like a map of
like
either grilling sessions that need done
to get the feature completed,
prototypes, uh or other tasks. And you
can see an example of this. I started
trying to build uh a new app here, and
this is the map that was produced. Uh
and you can see all these different sub
tickets that went into planning. Before,
if you were just doing like grow me with
docs or I was just trying to build my
own text back up, like this would have
been a ton of work. Like this is like
way too much for one text back or one
past over things. Uh some of these
you'll see are labeled as research. Uh
some other ones are going to be
grilling, which this was like an
interview session with me and the agent.
Some of these are prototyping
um or tasks. So, it'll go and create
throwaway implementations.
Um you can see here it has like the
proof of like I went and like
implemented a potential like interface
for this project. Like what do you think
about it? And it'll eventually build up
this text back in the way that I showed
before, but it goes through all of these
places that there was ambiguity in my
initial plan and it resolves all the
ambiguity over these different sessions
and then it'll eventually spit out kind
of issues for that agent to go
implement. So, I'm playing with that. Uh
I'll keep everyone updated on how I feel
about that in the next coming weeks, but
uh that's kind of my my workflow right
now.
>> Cool. Thanks for sharing. Uh this is
amazing because uh yeah, I keep thinking
that you and I have like fairly similar
output in terms of standards, but it is
so completely different from how I do
this. Thank you very much. I'm like
quite grateful.
>> I'm uh I'm excited to see how you guys
work. Work is work.
>> Yeah.
Well, thank you everyone for tuning in.
That's it for the next token episode
two, aka the third episode. At some
point we're going to have to figure out
uh this zero indexing problem we've got
ourselves into. Uh we'll be back in two
weeks with more opinions, predictions,
workflows, and uh whatever Sunil happens
to be tilted at at the time. Follow the
show wherever you're watching or
listening and tell us what you think in
the comments.
>> Uh
one of the things that's been on my mind
is I also want to talk about this
industry wide phenomenon of burnout
that's happening
and if I may be vulnerable for a second
I'm actually deep in the throws of
burnout like I've actually gone for the
last two weeks with approximately zero
lines of code which is weird for me
because I was averaging about 50 to
60,000 [music]
lines of code a week before that
and I'm actually so which is why I
started two weeks of leave you know you
see the ship burning and you immediately
some leave so
I saw that I saw the Odyssey today I did
this podcast with my friends and I'm
going to set up the Mac Mini that I
bought for open class six months ago
but I would love for us to like talk
about that and I'm looking forward to
seeing Reese's workflow I'm looking
forward to sharing my workflow but I do
want to talk about how we survive as an
industry through whatever the is
going on with everyone at the moment so
but still so grateful Dylan for you
showing us
how you do [music] things
>> Well go go get rested up and hopefully
recover here I'm not far behind you on
that front I am
I am straddling
burnout myself and I think once we get
artifacts to open beta here in the next
couple weeks I'm probably also going to
take
two weeks off just to kind of
step away and
let my
brain get away from the AI mush
but thank you everyone we will catch you
next time